employflorida.com 2016-11-15

# Employ Florida - Privacy Statement

### Privacy Statement

The Employ Florida Marketplace (EFM), as the State of Florida's official Workforce Labor Exchange, is strongly committed to maintaining the privacy of confidential information provided by its customers. For information on how to better protect your own privacy online, please see our Protect Yourself page. Personally identifying information is kept in a secure, encrypted database. Access to confidential information is restricted to authorized entities associated with the performance of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act of 2014. The operator of this website will not give, sell, or otherwise transfer electronic mail addresses maintained by EFM to any other party for the purposes of initiating, or enabling others to initiate, electronic mail messages. The collection, use and disclosure of your information are further governed by the following laws:

  * 42 U.S.C. § 405(C)(2)(c) (Social Security Act)
  * 5 U.S.C. § 552a (Privacy Act of 1974)
  * 5 U.S.C. § 552 (Freedom of Information Act)
  * 29 U.S.C. § 49, et seq. (Federal Employment Service)
  * 20 C.F.R. 652 (Establishment and Functioning of State Employment Services)
  * Chapter 119, Florida Statutes (Public Records)

**Providing your social security number is not mandatory.** If you would like to register without providing your social security number, please ask a local One-Stop representative for assistance. If you are not in a One-Stop center, please call 1-800-438-4128 for assistance. This process may take up to thirty minutes for staff to collect the necessary information and create a full registration in the EFM System.

For your protection, please do not use your social security number or FEIN when creating your user name.

Your information allows us to assist you in the following ways:

  * Personally identifying information, including name and social security number, is used to establish an EFM record.
  * Contact information such as home address, telephone number and electronic mail address is used to reach you when a suitable job is available or to schedule other employment-related services.
  * Personal information regarding age, ethnic group and gender is used strictly for statistical purposes to identify which segments of the population are being served. Based on this information, the system can be improved to better serve its users. Statistical information never identifies a specific user.
  * Employment information, including work history and occupational objectives, is used to match you with job openings. With your prior approval, this information can be provided directly to employers in the form of an electronic resume.
  * Service information, including a record of case-management services provided by One-Stop staff, is used to determine the appropriate type of service for you and to measure accomplishments.
  * Employer information such as position descriptions, job titles, number of openings, position locations, duties, hours, wages, and other skill and experience requirements, is used to match job seekers to job openings.

As a general rule, the EFM System does not collect personally identifying information about you when you visit the site unless you choose to provide such information. The information we receive depends upon which web forms you complete when using the EFM site.

For basic job opening and career information, you can use the EFM website as a "guest" without registering. To apply for positions or create a resume, however, registration is required.

For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, the EFM site employs software programs which monitor network traffic and identify unauthorized use of the site.

Like many websites, this site uses cookies, including third-party cookies, web beacons and similar technology to collect Log Data and voluntarily provided non-personally identifiable information including Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser version, date and time of visit, pages or screens visited, and other usage statistics. For mobile application users, when cookie technology is not available, advertising may use technologies that perform similarly to cookies. In this instance, the advertising platform can link the identifier of the advertising party across mobile applications and browsers in order to connect the data. For iOS 6 and above users, Apple’s Advertising Identifier is used. This is an identifier that is unique to your device but does not provide your Apple associated information. Additionally, information pertaining to the marketing campaign you interacted with will be sent back.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our website or mobile application.

For mobile applications on an Android device you can opt out of interested based ads by accessing the main Settings app and tapping "Google > Ads > Opt Out of interest based ads." On Apple devices, you can opt out by visiting the Settings menu on your device.

You can also opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page at <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.

## Online Advertising

We use the Google AdWords and Facebook platforms, including their remarketing services, to advertise across the internet. This means that advertisements for employflorida.com and the Employ Florida Mobile app may display when you visit other websites or are using other mobile applications. This program provides tailored advertisements. The way we are able to do this is by placing a third-party cookie or integrating a software development kit (SDK) into our mobile applications. The information that is sent back to Google and Facebook is used in the following ways:

  * To tell us if you have previously visited our site
  * To tell us if you have taken a specific action on our website or in our mobile app, including if you have registered with our website or if you have download our mobile applications
  * To tell us if you have not taken a specific action, like registering with our website or downloading our mobile applications

Personally identifiable information, such as full name, address and social security number, is not shared between [employflorida.com](https://www.employflorida.com/vosnet/Default.aspx) and Facebook or Google.

You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page at <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.

You can modify and disable the use of Facebook cookies. Here's how: <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>.

Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this site are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996.

* * *
